\$ 571-218-7157

inkedin.com/in/stevenhlederer

</> github.com/stevelederer

steve-lederer.com/imdb

Steve Lederer

Software Engineer

About

Technical Summary

iOS · Android

I'm a software engineer with more than 3 years of experience developing apps for both iOS and Android. I take pride in my attention to detail and exceptional ability to communicate technically complex information in simplified terms.

Swift • Objective-C • Java • Kotlin
Git • UIKit • Storyboards + Layout Editor • SwiftUI

Related Experience

Tech Lead - MassLight

November 2020 - Present

Manage a team of 5 people – including engineering and QA – currently developing 2 cross-platform apps (iOS & Android); work directly with clients to guide and implement the future of their mobile applications.

- Plan, estimate, and execute major project timelines
- Translate complex requirements into detailed tickets with consistent and testable acceptance criteria
- Coordinate the submission and review of app releases on Apple's App Store and Google Play
- Contributions resulted in 171% increase in unique active users and 22% increase in App Store ratings.

Software Engineer – *MassLight*

March 2019 - Present

Develop large-scale mobile applications for iOS and Android.

- Implement major new features including: content personalization, push notifications, biometric authentication, fitness tracking integration, and a full-app redesign including dark mode.
- Build and maintain end-to-end functionality of the app: networking, persistence, business logic, UI
- Re-architect legacy code and prep it for a more sustainable future of the product and team
- · Collaborate with backend developers to find best compromises between API and client applications
- Work with UI and UX designers to create consistent high-quality designs

Software Projects

SendTrack - (Solo Project) - Available in the App Store

February 2019

Developed this iOS app to allow users to easily share songs between different streaming services. Coded in Swift using UIKit and AVFoundation frameworks and accessing both the Apple Music and Spotify APIs.

- · Created custom algorithm to ensure songs were accurately matched
- · Added iMessage app extension for easy sharing and implemented StoreKit for an optional in-app tip
- Completed MVP of this project within 2 weeks

PhotoBox App - (Group Project)

January 2019

Led the planning and development of a photo sharing app for iOS. Fully responsible for creation and implementation of Firebase backend and controllers for MVC-based application. Uses Swift and UIKit.

- Worked with UI/UX designers to craft information design and simple app flow
- Supervised development team and provided valuable feedback in group meetings

Other Experience

Sound Editor - Technicolor Sound Services - Los Angeles, CA

2014 - 2018

Coordinated team of two junior sound editors, ensuring timely and quality completion of projects through strategic allocation of resources and workload prioritization. Served as foley and dialogue editor.

• Delivered assignments on time and within budget for clients including CBS, Fox, ABC, Hulu, and Netflix

Education

DevMountain – Salt Lake City, UT

2018 - 2019

Immersive iOS development program — Swift, Objective-C; UIKit, Foundation, CoreData, CloudKit; MVC, MVVM

Emerson College - Boston, MA

2007 - 2010

B.A. Communications – Focus in New Media & Audio Post Production